Yannick Gloster

90 Burleigh Court, Burlington Road, Dublin 4 | yannickgloster.com | yannickgloster@gmail.com | 083-043-3860

Objective

To contribute in specific projects or general support in a hi-tech, fast pace company. My expertise and interests are to focus on the field of computer science and gaining real-world work experience while continuing to learn new skills.

Education

Integrated Masters in Computer Science (in progress) (5 years) | April 2023 | Trinity College, Dublin, Ireland

- First Year Overall Mark: *I (Equivalent GPA 3.89)*
- Current coursework: Algorithms & Data Structures, Discrete Mathematics, Team Programing Project, Telecommunications, Concurrency & Operating Systems, Microprocessor Systems, Computer Architecture, Advanced French Language & Culture
- · First year coursework: Digital Logic Design, Electrotechnology, Telecommunications, Introduction to Programming, Programming Project, Introduction to Computing, Computer and Society, and Mathematics

Dos Pueblos High School | August 2014 - June 2018 | Goleta, CA

- · Graduated with a GPA of 4.1
- · SAT: 1480 / 1600 (Top 99% of the US) | ACT: 32 / 36
- 17 rigorous academic classes: AP (Advanced Placement)/IB (International Baccalaureate)/SBCC (Santa Barbara City College) Dual Enrolment classes

Experience

IT INTERN | DECKERS BRANDS | MAY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

- · Serviced 3,000 user workstations (Windows & MAC) & VMs. Wrote Powershell scripts to help automation for repetitive tasks for Windows Active Directory. Worked with the security team to get users set up on the company VPN and to unblock IPs and ports for the different software used by different teams in the company. Transitioned users on older Macbook Pros to the latest model. Helped with general IT activities.
- For reference, contact Julio Chacon at +1 805-967-7611 ext 1275 or at julio.chacon@deckers.com.

INTERN | ZYRIS (FORMERLY ISOLITE SYSTEMS) | DECEMBER 2018 - JANUARY 2019

 Helped organizing raw data to import into a commercial database and performed data clean up unifying several mismanaged databases. I used Excel and fuzzy functions to automatize data clean up. I also performed ad-hoc activities such as sorting and filing away purchase orders and helping with anything that was needed during the 4 weeks.

PROGRAMMING PROJECT | NEWS AGROGATOR | MARCH 2019 - MAY 2019

• Organized and programmed the back and front end to a news aggregator in a group of 4. In our project group, we were given gigabytes of data and our job was to parse through the data and present it in a visually interesting way.

"EVERY 15 MINUTES" | 30 MIN SHORT FILM | JANUARY - FEBRUARY 2018

· I co-wrote, co-directed, co-shot, and co-edited a short film about youth drunk driving through a program with the State of California. The film was shown to the entire senior class and had a powerful impact on students. Through this project, not only did I show my talent in video production, but also in team management and working with other professionals such as Santa Barbara County Sheriff's Office, Santa Barbara Cottage Hospital, and more. The full film currently has 34,000 views on YouTube and can be found here - https://youtu.be/AKya9w4UpyE.

ATHLETICS | SAILOR & INSTRUCTOR | 2009 - PRESENT

• Began racing in sailing at age 9. Over the last 5 years, I have competed in 3 World Championships, 2 North American championship, 1 UK youth national championships and 1 US national championships. In 2017, I placed 2nd Youth in the World RS Aero series (France) and in 2019, I placed 1st in my fleet (division) in the North American Championships. I transfer my competitive spirit in seeking improvements into my work. I have also completed the technical sailing training requirements, CPR-First aid certification in the US and in France and passed my motorboat driving permit to become a sailing instructor in France. I am fully certified for teaching sailing anywhere in France after I completed a 2 weeks hands-on instructing course. Becoming a sailing instructor is the opportunity to continue developing my leadership and teaching skills.

Skills & Abilities

TECHNICAL AND OTHER SKILLS

- · Programming Languages: Java, C/C++, ARM, Matlab, HTML, CSS
- · Git (Github) & Subversion
- · Proficiency in Adobe Premier Pro and Adobe After Effects for video editing, color grading, and light VFX
- Technical Camera Skills (directing, shot composition, etc.)
- · Strong understanding how technology works together and can easily learn and figure out new technologies
- · Language (Fluent): English, French

SELF-DRIVEN

• I can quickly adapt to new environments and ideas and can navigate through complex problems while simultaneously learning in a new environment. I am good at figuring things out as I go along. I will not quit until I reached a satisfactory solution.

LEADERSHIP

· In High School, I was selected to be the producer (the leadership role) of our student run and produced TV/Video production class of 45 students. In this role, I was responsible for and led the effort to adapt new technologies in live video production to improve our 7 min daily news video broadcast for all 2,000+ students on campus. I helped those around me to achieve greater things while simultaneously learning more myself.

COMMUNICATION

- I have been recognized to have strong verbal and presentation skills. I am comfortable developing and preparing presentations and use them to organize and motivate others. I am able to take a complex or challenging project and articulate the concepts, tasks, and ideas into smaller achievable goals.
- I am comfortable working with cross-functional teams and understand the value of multiple inputs to achieve something greater.

Selected Key Attributes

- · Self-driven
- · Team player
- · Creative thinker
- · Positive outlook
- Entrepreneur

- Recognized leader
- · Effective presenter
- · Bring task to completion
- · Focused, organized
- · Curious, enjoy learning
- Video filming
- · Video editing
- Programming
- · Basic circuit design
- Technical skills / hardware